War has cost them their innocence... Freedom will cost them their blood.
The Wind That Shakes the Barley is a drama, war film directed by Ken Loach.
In 1920s Ireland young doctor Damien O'Donovan prepares to
depart for a new job in a London hospital.
As he says his goodbyes at a friend's farm, British Black
and Tans arrive, and a young man is killed.
Damien joins his brother Teddy in the Irish Republican Army, but political
events are soon set in motion that tear the brothers apart.
Damien, played by Cillian Murphy.
Teddy, played by Pádraic Delaney.
Dan, played by Liam Cunningham.
Sinead, played by Orla Fitzgerald.
Peggy, played by Mary O'Riordan.
Bernadette, played by Mary Murphy.
The Wind That Shakes the Barley is a 2006 war drama film directed by Ken Loach, set during
the Irish War of Independence (1919–1921) and the Irish Civil War (1922–1923).
Written by long-time Loach collaborator Paul Laverty, the film tells the fictional story of two County Cork brothers, Damien (Cillian Murphy) and Teddy O'Donovan (Pádraic Delaney), who join the
Irish Republican Army to fight for Irish independence from the United Kingdom, only for the two brothers to then find themselves on opposite sides during the subsequent Irish Civil War.
The film takes its title from Robert Dwyer Joyce's "The Wind That Shakes the Barley", a
song set during the 1798 rebellion in Ireland and featured early in the film.
Widely praised, the film won the Palme d'Or at the 2006 Cannes Film Festival.
Loach's biggest box office success as of 2007, the film did well around the world and set a record in
Ireland as the highest-grossing Irish-made independent film, until surpassed by The Guard.
The film explores themes of guerrilla warfare, civil war,
sibling relationship, england, underground.
The tone is emotional.